# 广东 佛山 拍摄于2020年1月初
Foshan, Guangdong (Recorded in early January 2020)
# 哈喽 雪鱼现在在佛山
Hello! Xueyu is in Foshan right now
# 今天中午呢 我们将要去一个农庄
We are going to a farm this afternoon
# 去品尝靓汤
To try some amazing soups
# 它这个靓汤就是用瓦罐做出来的
The soups are cooked in clay pots
# 罐子特别大 汤也特别多
The pots are large and the soups are plentiful
# 我们今天中午就锁定 靓汤
That's what we are aiming this afternoon, soups!
# 到饭店的门口了
We’ve arrived at the entrance of the restaurant
# 你不仅能够闻到香味
You can smell the aroma of the soups,
# 还能够听到来在于肚子咕咕叫的声音
and also hear the noise that your stomach is making
# 一进来 你就能看到10几个炭炉子在燃烧
Once you go into the restaurant, you can see more than 10 stoves working
# 上面在煲汤 闻着就很香
The soups are boiling and are fragrant
# 瞬间就能感受到
You can immediately understand
# 来广东一定要喝汤的这种气息
the soup culture in Guangdong
# 正好今天的温度是12摄氏度
Coincidentally, the temperature is around 12 °C today
# 温度比较低 喝汤特别合适
It’s kinda cold today, having soup is extremely suitable
# 我们点一个吧
Let’s order some soups!
# 每一煲汤 都是有特定的食材的
There are specific ingredients for each pots of soups
# 这个是煲老鸽
This is pigeon soup
# 好像是一整只鸽子放进去的
It seems like there is an entire pigeon in it
# 哇 好香啊
Wow! It’s so fragrant
# 看颜色就觉得非常有食欲
The colour is really appetizing
# 不过这个煲是别人的
But this pot of soup is ordered by another person
# 咱们现在是吃不到
We can’t have it now
# 可以先看一下 解解眼馋
However, it’s harmless to take a look
# 我们再来看一看 这个煲的是什么
Let’s have a look at the ingredients in another pot of soup
# 底料都被捞出来了 热气腾腾的
The ingredients have been taken out and it’s still steaming hot
# 这里面有赤豆 粉葛 瘦肉
There are red beans, kudzu roots and lean pork
# 哇 是煲鲮鱼
Wow! It’s dace fish
# 小哥说 虽然现在只有12个汤
The waiter just told me that there are 12 soups being served right now
# 但是很多汤的菜谱都在脑子里
But many recipes of other soups are memorized in their minds
# 摆出来的只是一部分
Only some of them are showed
# 很多的时候 会根据季节的不同
A lot of times, they would alter the soup ingredients
# 变化不同的汤品
According to seasonal changes
# 菜单的这一页写的就是靓汤了
The various soups are written on this page of the menu
# 这边比较特色的是靓汤是
The signature soup here is
# 花生眉豆煲鸡脚
chicken feet soup with peanuts and black-eyed peas(cowpeas)
# 这个是我们待会要点的
We’re gonna order this later
# 咱们不能老喝汤 也得吃点菜吧
We can’t have soups only, we need some other dishes too
# 哇
Wow!
# 你好点餐
Hi, I would like to order something
# 要一个眉豆花生煲鸡脚
One chicken feet soup with peanuts and black-eyed peas
# 这个有吧
You’re serving this today right?
# 再要一个炒肥肠
And also a plate of stir-fried pork intestines
# 汤渣分离
Removing the soup residue
# 简单调味
Seasoning it
# 我们的汤要来了 来了
Our soup is almost served
# 哇 好大的坛子啊
Wow! The pot is huge
# 先上来的是汤渣
The soup ingredients are first served
# 然后是调料
Then the sauce
# 最后上来了一大煲的汤
Last but not least, the huge pot of soup
# 要趁热喝哦
Remember to drink it when it’s still warm
# 好的
Okay
# 真是让人感觉幸福的汤
This soup is comforting
# 这汤看起来好白
The soup is milky and whitish (indicating it has been cooked for a long time and is fully emulsified)
# 里面就是有植物的豆香味
There is the fragrant smell of peas
# 还有一些花生的味道
And the aroma of peanuts in it
# 我能够喝出来的味道有点像植物奶
It tastes similar to vegan milk
# 真是鲜 香 浓 甜
It’s full of umami flavour, aromatic, thick and sweet
# 这个汤渣就是有眉豆 花生和鸡脚
The soup residue includes chicken feet, peanuts and black-eyed peas
# 还放了一些煮汤的料（姜等）
And also some minor ingredients such as ginger
# 没想到里面还有大块的骨头和肉
Surprisingly, there are also big pieces of bones and meat in it
# 其实煲汤就是无骨不浓 无肉不香
In fact, bone gives thickness, meat gives aroma
# 这个汤都做到了
This soup achieves all the requirements
# 这个汤煲得时间太长了
The soup has been cooked for so long
# 像鸡爪 用筷子一夹
Using chopsticks,
# 根本就夹不出来一个完整的形状
You can’t pick up the entire chicken foot
# 我夹哪个地方 就从哪个地方开始断开
It would break into pieces when you grab it
# 这个汤没有很重的味道
The soup is not heavily seasoned
# 如果需要吃汤料的话 需要和酱油来搭配
If you want to eat the soup ingredients, you can eat them together with the soy sauce
# 店里面还有很多的美食
There are plenty of other delicious food served in the restaurant
# 这次吃得差不多了
I’m kinda full
# 咱们下次再来吧
Let’s try the other delicacies next time
# 刚才和小哥聊天的时候
When I was chatting with the few men just now
# 本来很开朗的一个人
They were friendly and nice initially
# 但是当镜头对着他的时候
But when the camera is facing them,
# 几个人全跑光了
All of them ran away
# 最后只能我自己一个人说
At last only me myself is talking to the camera
# 好了 今天的视频就到这儿了 拜拜
Okay, that’s it for today’s video, Bye bye!.